（男）スーパー高校生が
こっちもいける口だったとはね
Didn't expect the super high-schooler
to like guys, too.
また～？
Again? Twist my arm...
ヤじゃないけどさ
（２人の激しいあえぎ声）
（男）ちょっと！ 激し…！
Hey, that's too much.
Junichi.
（幸田(こうだ)燃寛(もゆる)）純一(じゅんいち)…
純一…
Junichi.
純一　純一
純一　純一… 純一～っ
Junichi. Junichi. Junichi!
ちょっと！ 俺 純一じゃ…
Who the hell's Junichi?
あっ！？
（幸田の嗚咽）
（幸田）うあああ～っ
（幸田マン）グアアア～ッ！
ヴォオオオオーッ！！
（幸田の泣き声）
ハアッ
（荒い息）
（すすり泣き）
Neither Demon Nor Human
-Here.
（牧村(まきむら)美樹(みき)）はい
（陸上部員１）はい
はい
（美樹）はい
-Here.
はい
（陸上部員１）はい
-Here.
はい
（美樹）はい
-Here.
（陸上部員２）
あれ 練習なんないよな
-How is that practice?
-Can't help it.
（陸上部員３） しかたないっすよ
抜擢された２人がいないっすから
The other two runners aren't here.
（陸上部員４）
ミーコ 既読つかないなあ
（バトンの練習の声）
-It says Miko still hasn't read her text.
-Fudo's always absent, too.
（バトンの練習の声）
（陸上部員５）
不動(ふどう)くん 休みがちだし
（陸上部員６）
せっかく選手に選ばれたのにね
And after they were both
chosen to run.
（陸上部員６）
せっかく選手に選ばれたのにね
（バトンの練習の声）
（英語）
（英語：雷沼(らいぬま)）
オタワの会議以来だね
（英語：飛鳥 了(あすか りょう)）
あの発表には驚きました
人類以外の知的生命体とは
（英語）
（了）幸田は悪魔だ
その仮面を暴いてやる
Koda is a demon.
I'm going to unmask him.
世界が悪魔の存在に気づく
The world will see that demons exist,
and an age of fearing
隣人が悪魔かもしれないと
怯える日々が始まるんだ
that your neighbors
are demons will begin.
Hey.
（不動 明(あきら)）なあ 悪魔には
本当に心がないのか
Do demons really not have hearts?
（了）心はある
They do. But...
しかし良心という
他人をいたわる心がないんだ
they have no conscience
to care about others.
（キーボードを打つ音）
（明）良心？
Conscience?
（了）いたわりや情け
共感 愛 そういうものだ
Things like consideration,
mercy, empathy, and love.
しかし あの２人…
But those two were...
あっ…
うくく… うおああ…！
（デビルマン）
ウアアアーッ！ ヌウッ！
よし
Good.
お前があいつに液体を飲ませ
俺が映像を流す
Make him drink the liquid,
and I'll get the footage out.
悪魔に姿を変えたあいつが
外へ逃げ出したら―
When he turns into a demon
and escapes outside,
お前があいつを始末するんだ
get rid of him.
競技場の映像は世界に配信される
The footage will spread around the world.
（美樹）明くん
（明）んっ
Akira.
（美樹）練習 出てきなよ
Come to practice.
せっかくリレーに選ばれたんだから
You're in the relay, after all.
（明）ああ…
（明の足音）
何かあった？
Did something happen?
（明の足音）
Something did, right?
あったよね
（明）変か？
Am I acting weird?
（美樹）明らかにね
Totally.
いいか悪いかは おいといて
Forget about if that's good or bad...
（明）は…
はあ…
If something's up,
I'm here to talk.
（美樹）
何かあったのなら話せよ
んっ？
俺たち家族だろ
We're family, right?
あ…
ああ
Yeah.
えへっ
（明）今は話せねえ
けど いつか話す
I can't tell you now, but I will one day.
（美樹）
聞いたことあるな～ そのセリフ
I've heard that line before.
４継 私が３番手
明くんがアンカーよ
In the 4-by-100-meter,
I run third and you're the anchor.
私がバトンを渡すから
ちゃんと受け取って走ってね
When I pass the baton,
make sure you grab it and run, okay?
約束だぞ
That's a promise.
ああ
Yeah.
（ミーコ）ミキ 明日からあんたが
ミーコになるんだ！
Miki, you're the new Miko as of tomorrow.
ハハハハハ
アハハハハハ！
KOSHIEN TRACK AND FIELD
CHECK-IN BOOTH
（車のドアが開く音）
（ウェブプロデューサー）
おはようございます 了さん
Good morning, Ryo.
It's a huge turnout.
（了）すごい人出ですね
幸田選手だけでなく―
It's not just Mr. Koda.
There's lots of others being talked about,
山代(やましろ)ジュニアや牧村美樹など―
最近いろいろ話題になっている
選手が多いですからね
like Yamashiro Jr. and Miki Makimura,
イベントの全容は
地上波に任せて―
Let's leave the big picture
to the TV broadcast,
私たちは あくまで幸田選手に
集中する感じでいきましょう
and keep our focus on Mr. Koda.
（陸上部員１）おっ 川高(かわこう)いるぞ
There's Kawa High.
（陸上部員２）
いないっすねえ スーパー高校生
-No super high-schooler.
-Does he get special treatment?
（陸上部員１）特待か？
個室とかあんじゃねえの？
（足音）
Off in a private room?
あっ
仲悪(わり)いのか？
-Do they not get along or something?
-There's all sorts of rumors.
（陸上部員２）なんか いろいろ
ウワサありますよねー
（幸田）ん？
（明）前にテレビで見た
I saw you on TV before.
話しかけるな
Don't talk to me.
空港で泣いてたよな
（幸田）あっ
You were crying at the airport.
What the--?
（陸上部員１）何あいつ
（陸上部員２）やべっ
-This is bad.
-Why would he bring that up?
（川高生徒１）
その話題 持ち出すか？
And he wasn't crying, either.
（川高生徒２）
それに泣いてなかったろ
な… なんだとおっ！
What did you just say?!
Stop it, Koda!
（クドウ）やめろ 幸田
Don't talk to him before the race.
試合前に話しかけないでくれ
緊張してるんだから
He's nervous.
You...
お前―
悲しかったんだよな
were sad, weren't you?
そして今も 泣いてる
（幸田）なっ…！？
And you're still crying now.
（陸上部員１）
何言ってんだ　何あいつ？
What the hell is he saying?
（陸上部員２）ワケわかんねえ
I don't get it.
はあ はあ はあ はあ…
うあああーっ！
黙れ 黙れ！
Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up!
黙れーっ！！
-Hey.
-Pardon me.
（クドウ）おい！
（了）失礼！
なっ！？
初めまして 幸田さん
飛鳥です
Nice to meet you, Mr. Koda. I'm Asuka.
あ… ああ
（明がロッカーから出る音）
WOMEN'S LOCKER ROOM
（ドアが乱暴に閉まる音）
（女子たち）はっ
フッ
（女子）ん？
（美樹）ん！
ええっ？
あー？
チッ
ふんっ
（女子）ひえ～ 怖～い
So scary!
（女子たち）ちょっと 待ってよ
え～ ちょっと待って
Hey, wait.
-How come?
-Miko, what you just did was--
（美樹）ミーコ 今の…
（ミーコ）態度悪いって？
So, I've got a bad attitude?
勝負しよう
スペシャル４継のタイムで
Let's have our
4-by-100 times do the talking.
いいよ 何賭ける？
Fine. Name the stakes.
A cake from Tsukihiro, or Monday's lunch?
つきひろのケーキか
月曜のランチ？
（ミーコ）名前
（美樹）え…
Your name.
私が勝ったら 私がミキをもらう
If I win, I get to use the name Miki.
（女性記者）失礼します
Excuse me. Is Miki Makimura here?
牧村美樹選手
いらっしゃいますか？
はい
Yes.
（女性記者）
インタビューよろしいですか？
May I interview you?
（美樹）はいっ すみません
Absolutely.
用意ができましたので あちらで
We're all set.
Could you come over here?
（美樹）ごめん あとで！
Talk to you later.
人気者は大変ね
Must be hard to be popular.
はっ！？
（ウェブプロデューサー）
私のイチオシは―
My eyes will be on the enchantress
of track-and-field, Miki Makimura,
陸上界の魔女
牧村美樹ちゃん
Japan's first female
under 11 seconds in the 100-meter,
日本女子初の10秒台も夢じゃない
スプリンターでありながら―
自由なＳＮＳも
女子高生に大人気
she's also huge on social media
among high school girls.
すでに注目株ですが―
She's already a fan favorite,
ホント性格もさっぱりしていて
かわいいんですよね
with a great personality
who is also really cute.
（ガビ）ホレたか？ 牧村美樹に
You in love with Miki Makimura?
（ワム）殺すぞ
Shut up.
俺はホレたけどな
Well, I'm into her.
え？
Mom, it's gonna start soon.
（牧村太郎(たろう)）
お母さん もうすぐ始まるよ！
（ウェブプロデューサー）
さて ここからは―
And now, I pass the baton to Ryo
and the first Japanese
了さんにバトンタッチ
日本男子初の
９秒台をたたき出した―
to break the 10-second barrier,
for a conversation with another phenom,
the track-and-field superstar Koda.
スーパー高校生―
幸田選手との
天才対談です
（ワム）ああ？
こいつ…
This guy.
幸田選手の走りを見ていると
人間ではない―
When I see you run,
I feel like I'm watching a creature
that's not human.
まるで別の生き物を見ているような
気がするんです
褒められてるんですよね
-That's a compliment, right?
-Of course.
もちろん
ん…
食事にも気を使って？
-Are you on a strict diet?
-No, not really.
いえ 特には
ふむ それでは
I see. Well, then...
飲んでもらえますか？
...how about a drink?
契約されてるスポンサー飲料ですよ
It's one of your sponsor's beverages.
カメラ目線で ひと口だけ
Just look at the camera
and take a sip.
はあ…
プハッ
ご協力 感謝します
I appreciate your cooperation.
（開会の音楽）
（テレビ司会者）
いよいよ始まりました
It has finally started.
（開会の音楽）
高校陸上アスリートの祭典
陸上甲子園
The pinnacle of high-school athletics,
Koshien Track and Field!
高校陸上アスリートの祭典
陸上甲子園
今回の主役は何と言っても―
All theories aside,
today's star is the super high-schooler
with five youth records,
５つの世界ユース記録を
たたき出したスーパー高校生―
幸田燃寛(もゆる)選手！
Moyuru Koda.
（ウェブプロデューサー）
定点カメラは
こちらでスイッチできますから
You can switch to the static camera here.
海外からも すごいアクセスですよ
There's a lot of overseas access.
That's the power of Koda.
さすが幸田選手
NICONICO LIVE STREAM
（クドウ）
さっきのバカにはビビったよ
That idiot scared me,
pissing off Koda like that.
幸田怒らすなんてよ
（タカハマ）コーチみたいに
ボコられたら たまんねえぞ
I hope he doesn't
get beaten up like Coach.
（クドウ）
おい こんなとこで言うなよ
Hey, don't say that here.
事故ってことになってんだから
The story is it was an accident.
（タカハマ）口止め 口止め
I have to stay quiet, huh?
Is Koda that important?
そんなに幸田様が大事かね
（トイレを流す音）
（クドウ）あ…
（タカハマ）あっ
You...
（クドウ）お前…
（タカハマ）さっきのバカ
The idiot.
幸田のこと
俺に詳しく聞かせろ
Koda.
Tell me more about him!
（クドウ）あいつ 去年の秋から
いきなり速くなったんだ
Last fall he got fast all of a sudden.
それまでは純一の足元にも
全然及ばなかったのにさ
He was no match for Junichi up till then.
あいつら幼なじみで
They were childhood friends.
（タカハマ）記録だけじゃないんだ
様子も全然変わっちまって―
It's not just the record.
His appearance totally changed, too.
同じ人間とは思えねえよ
Like he's a different person.
（クドウ）
純一が死んでから特にひどくて
It's been really bad since Junichi died.
（タカハマ）あんな殺され方
したから 無理ねえけど
Hard to blame him,
considering how Junichi died.
（事葉純一）燃寛―
Moyuru.
Let's compete on the world stage together.
一緒に世界に行こうな
大丈夫　お前は才能あるよ
You'll be fine. You have talent.
俺が保証する
I guarantee it.
えへっ
（すすり泣き）
うううう…
うあああああ…
（泣き声）
（テレビ司会者）
今年はエキシビションとして―
As an exhibition,
we have a special 4-person race.
スペシャル４継を用意しました
A mixed 4-by-100-meter relay.
男女混合400メートル
どこがスペシャルかと言いますと
第１コースの幸田選手には―
What's special is that Koda,
in the first lane,
最初から最後まで
１人で走っていただきます
will run the whole race by himself.
４人がかりなら―
Let's see how
four normal high-schoolers fare
普通の高校生が
スーパー高校生を倒せるのか？
against a super high-schooler.
（歓声）
To fire the starting pistol,
スタートの合図は―
今期から始まる注目のドラマ
「ドラッグレディ」の―
please welcome the star of
the upcoming drama Drug Lady,
ヒロイン役 AYUMI(あゆみ)さんに
お願いしています
Ayumi!
（AYUMI）よーい！
Get set!
（歓声）
幸田選手 飛び出したー！
Koda explodes off the block!
（歓声）
すごい スタートダッシュ！
An amazing opening sprint!
幸田選手らしいですね
お遊びの企画でも 手は抜かない
This is classic Koda.
He doesn't hold back,
even in an exhibition.
Go for it!
（陸上部員１）ファイトー！
あんたにも脇役になってもらう
I've got a supporting role for you, too.
（陸上部員２）ミーコ！
（ミーコ）チッ
Miko!
（陸上部員１）ファイトー！
Go! Go!
ミーコって…
Don't...
You can do it, Miko!
（陸上部員３）
ファイト！　ミーコ！
呼ぶなあーっ！
...call me Miko!
（幸田）あっ
ファイト！ ミーコ！
You've got this, Miko!
すごい！ たった１人
幸田選手を追っていくのは―
The only one on the heels of Koda,
in the green,
緑のユニフォーム
the heroine of the track,
Miki Makimura.
陸上界のヒロイン
牧村美樹ちゃんだ！
It's not her.
Makimura is running next.
（ＡＤ）違います
牧村はその次です
あっ
（ミーコ）俺が黒田(くろだ)ミキ
I'm Miki Kuroda.
本物のミキだ！
I'm the real Miki.
チッ…
なああっ
はっ
ミーコ！
Miko!
あっ
Akira?
明くん！？
あっ
兄ちゃん すごい！
Look at him go!
（テレビ司会者）なんと！
上学(かみがく)の不動選手が追いついた！
Fudo from Kamioka Academy has caught up.
But...he's supposed to be the anchor.
しかし彼はアンカーのはず…
（明）てめえの中に獣が棲んでる
（幸田）なっ…
There's a beast inside you.
そいつが 毎日毎日
爆発しそうでたまらねえ
It's on the verge
of exploding everyday.
叫びたい　壊したい　犯したい
You want to scream, destroy, violate.
しかし みんなにバレるのが怖い
そうだろ！
But you're scared of everyone finding out.
Right?
How?
なんで！？
（明）俺も そうだからさ！
Because I'm the same.
はっ
（歓声）
（スタート音）
はっ
Ryo.
（明）了…
（幸田）はあ はあ…
（テレビ局員１）
なんだ あの映像は
-What the hell?
-Stop it! It'll be a broadcast scandal!
（テレビ局員２）
止めろ　放送事故になるぞ！
Stop it, Ryo.
やめろ 了　作戦は中止だ！
Abort the mission!
ドリンクはすり替えてない！
そんなことしても…
I didn't switch his drink.
Even if we did...
明 もう始まったんだ
Akira...
It's already started.
（幸田の荒い息）
（幸田）はあ はあ…
はあ はあ…
イヤだ…
No.
イヤだ
（ミーコ）あっ
（美樹）えっ？
（幸田）イヤだ
No.
（幸田マン）うおおおおっ
（幸田）イヤだあっ！
（明）はっ
No!
（幸田）イヤだ…
イヤだあっ
No!
イヤだあーっ！！
（人々の悲鳴）
（明）幸田！
Koda!
幸田！
幸田ーっ！
Koda!
Stop!
やめろ！
Ryo!
了ーっ！！
イヤーっ！
Open it!
開けてーっ！！
グオオオー！
（女）イヤ！ イヤッ！！
あ… あ
（ミーコ）はっ
ミーコ！ 早くこっち！
Miko, hurry. This way.
あいつは逃げようとしているだけだ
了！ 予定どおり外へ出せ
He's just trying to run away.
Ryo, get him out of here like we planned.
Open the gate!
扉を開けろ！
&lrm;（音楽）
RELAXING TUNES
（人々の悲鳴）
Help! Help me!
（地響き）
グルルルル…
グアアアアーッ！
（アナウンサー）えっ… えー
いったんスタジオに
カメラを戻します
And now back to the studio.
えっ？
Yes. But...
はい　 いや しかし…
失礼いたしました
いったん コマーシャルに
My apologies.
Time for a commercial break.
あー 水分ほしいなー
I need to rehydrate.
Oh, it's Ene-Vital.
ENEVITAL(エネバイタル)じゃん
-Miki.
-Akira.
（牧村ノエル）美樹！
（牧村亜樹子(あきこ)）明くん！
Awesome.
かっけ～！
We'll stop the broadcast.
しかたない 放送は中止だ
Don't.
（了）止めるな
しかし…
-But--
-Don't you get it?
分からないのか？
地上波が放送をやめた今―
With the TV broadcast stopped,
我々だけが
この放送を流しているんだ
we're the only ones showing this footage.
すごいヒット数になるぞ
We'll get a lot of hits.
う…
これは僕の番組です
This is my program.
何かあれば 僕が責任をとりますよ
If something happens,
I'll take responsibility.
PLEASE STANDBY
（ワム）なんで終わんだよ！
What happened?
説明しろよ どうなってんだよ！
-Explain what's going on.
-It's still streaming on my phone.
（ガビ）
おい モバイルは続いてるぞ
（ウェブプロデューサー）
ご覧ください
Look at this.
幸田選手が突然…
It appears Koda suddenly turned
into some sort of beast.
獣に変わってしまった
ように見えます
実際 変わったんですよ
（ウェブプロデューサー）え？
He actually transformed.
幸田選手は―
Mr. Koda...
悪魔なんです
is a demon.
（女子高生たち）悪魔？
（カップル）悪魔？
A demon?
-A demon? What a joke.
-It's just a trick.
（女子高生１）悪魔って 笑える
（女子高生２）引っかけだよ
They say Asuka is really a professor.
（女子高生３）
でも飛鳥ってホントに教授だって
-WHAT'S HE TALKING ABOUT?
-ASUKA'S HOT EVEN IN TIMES LIKE THIS.
-IT EXPLAINS KODA'S DEMON-LIKE ABILITIES.
-SO MUCH BLOOD.
-I'VE SEEN THAT DEMON ON DEVILMAN!
-SO SCARY.
-THIS LOOKS REAL.
-IT'S A REAL DEMON.
DEMON. DEMON. DEMON.
（ノン）あのバカを
早くなんとかしろ！
-Hurry and do something about that idiot.
-What do you plan to do?
（悪魔たちの声）
（激しい打撃音）
It was no accident. This was plotted.
（ヌガ）偶然じゃない
謀られたんだ これは！
（英語）
（了）あとは頼んだぞ 明
I leave the rest to you, Akira.
（英語：了）
トリックでないことは―
会場の皆さんが
証言してくれるでしょう
（英語：了）たくさんの証拠を
私は用意しています
悪魔は実在するのです
皆さんの すぐそばに…
（電話の呼び出し音）
俺だ
It's me.
（了）明
Hey, Akira.
悪魔なら殺したよ
I killed the demon.
（了）ご苦労
Good job.
明日から忙しくなるぞ
よく休んでおけ
We'll be busy starting tomorrow.
Get some rest.
（通話が切れる音）
（大きな足音）
グルル…
グオオオオオオ！
（足音）
グルルル…
&lrm;
You're not human.
お前は人間じゃない
（デビルマン）だが 悪魔でもない
But you're not a demon, either.
グルルルル…
お前は―
You're a Devilman!
デビルマンだ！
And I'm going...
お前は―
俺が―
救ってやる！
to save you!
&lrm;
&lrm;日本語字幕　後藤 太郎
Subtitles by
Kristine Kenmochi